welcome back to new every day my name is
dobrodošli nazad u novi svaki dan moje ime je
Carrie and my name is Jen and this is
Carrie i moje ime je Jen i ovo je
the final part of our four-part series
završni deo naše serije od četiri dela
on adventure begins so stay tuned be
na avanturi počinje tako da ostanete u toku
right back
pravo nazad
welcome back to new every day so why do
dobrodošli nazad u novi svaki dan pa zašto
you tune did really really are we're so
Vi ste zaista napravili da ste tako
glad that you actually listened to us
drago mi je da ste nas saslušali
and get to share with what we're
i podelimo sa nama ono što smo
learning because every time we do this
učiti jer svaki put kada to radimo
we learned something hey Jen yeah and
naučili smo nešto Jen da i
for the last four weeks well three weeks
poslednje četiri nedelje i tri nedelje
we've been talking about the adventure
pričali smo o avanturi
begins and when we first started talking
počinje i kada smo prvi put počeli da pričamo
about this all I could think about was
o svemu tome sam mislio
Frodo Baggins oh lord of the ring in in
Frodo Bagins oh, gospodaru prstena
The Hobbit The Hobbit I mean and where
Hobit Hobit Mislim, i gde
he wants nothing to do with the
on ne želi da ima ništa sa tim
adventure and then Gandalf tap tap tap
avantura, a zatim Gandalf tapnite slavinu
you know saying basically fred was like
znate da je u osnovi fred bio
no I don't want to go on Frodo know
Ne, ne želim da idem na Frodo
Bilbo Bilbo Bilbo he says no I don't
Bilbo Bilbo Bilbo kaže da ne
want to be part of this and Gandalf like
Želim da budem deo ovog i Gandalfa
what aren't you the Son and he starts
ono što nisi ti Sin i on počinje
saying giving him all these reasons why
izgovarajući mu sve te razloge zašto
he said gone why he should go on this
rekao je da je otišao zbog toga
adventure like he has been basically
avantura kao što je u osnovi
equipped to go his DNA has equipped him
opremljen da ode njegov DNK ga je opremio
to go on this adventure and he's just
ići na ovu avanturu i on je samo
like no no and then the dwarves show up
kao ni ne i onda se pojavljuju patuljci
and the team is built this team is built
i tim je izgrađen ovaj tim je izgrađen
and then Frodo you know you see this
a onda Frodo znaš da vidiš ovo
image of him while least in the movie of
slika o njemu dok je najmanje u filmu
him flying down and they're like oh are
njega leti dole i oni su kao oh su
you going Bilbo my goodness Bilbo
ćeš Bilbo moj Bože Bilbo
running down he's like I'm going on an
trčao je kao da idem na
adventure and he doesn't even really
avantura i on uopšte i ne zna
know what the adventure is yeah um and
znam šta je to avantura
so then he joins the dwarfs he signed
pa se onda pridružio patuljama koje je potpisao
the page and he's in for the he's in for
na stranici i on je za to što je on za
the adventure right to the very end yes
avantura do samog kraja da
and when we're talking about the
i kada govorimo o
disciples and the people who came to
učenici i ljudi koji su došli
Christ after the disciples they are
Hristos po učenicima oni su
embarking on this great adventure and
krećemo u ovu veliku avanturu i
they've just received the Holy Spirit we
oni su upravo primili Svetog Duha mi
had a bread about the day of Pentecost
imao je hljeb na dan Pedesetnice
so they received the Holy Spirit so now
tako su i sada primili Svetog Duha
they've got the gas in the car they had
oni imaju plin u automobilu koji su imali
a high vision the vision which is like
vizija je vizija koja je takva
Jesus came yeah go tell everyone a bow
Isus je došao i rekao je svima luk
tell everyone about the kingdom about
reći svima o kraljevstvu
the fact that Jesus came and we can have
činjenicu da je Isus došao i da možemo
life through the Sun and become children
život kroz Sunce i postanite djeca
of God yeah so again now what so now
od Boga da, pa opet sada, šta sada
they're just getting started we're in
tek su počeli da ulazimo
the book of Acts chapter 2 yeah and the
knjigu Dela apostolska poglavlje 2 i da
heading just before verse 40 is called a
naslov neposredno pre stiha 40 se naziva a
vital church grows
vitalna crkva raste
hmm yes a vital church grows of mind it
hmm da vitalna crkva raste uma
says the Fellowship of the believers
kaže Društvo vernika
okay which is interesting because we've
Dobro, što je interesantno jer smo
talked about Jesus gave the vision he
razgovarali o Isusu dao viziju on
built the team he gave the power and so
izgradio je tim koji je dao moć i tako
now we're back to so now had to reach to
sada smo se vratili, tako da sada moramo doći do
know what so maybe can I just read this
Znaš šta možda mogu da pročitam
here too sure so starting verse 40 and
ovde previše siguran da počinju stih 40 i
with many other words he testified and
sa mnogim drugim rečima koje je svedočio
sorted them saying be saved from this
sortirali bi ih kako bi se spasili od ovoga
perverse generation so this is Peter
perverzna generacija tako da je ovo Peter
talking still right then those who
govoreći još uvek pravo onda oni koji
gladly received his words were baptized
rado je primio njegove riječi i krstio se
and that day about three thousand souls
i toga dana oko tri hiljade duša
were added to them and they continued
dodani su im i oni su nastavili
steadfastly in the Apostles doctrine and
postojano u apostolskoj doktrini i
fellowship in the breaking of bread and
zajedništvo u razbijanju hleba i
in prayers then fear came upon every
u molitvama je strah dolazio na svakoga
soul and many wonders and signs were
duša i mnoga čudesa i znaci
done through the apostles now all who
učinjeno preko apostola sada svi koji
believed were together and had all
vjerovali su zajedno i imali su sve
things in common I love this part and
stvari zajedničke volim ovaj dio i
sold their possessions and goods and
prodali svoju imovinu i robu i
divided them among all as anyone had
podelio ih je među svima kao što je iko imao
meat so continuing daily with one Accord
meso tako nastavlja svakodnevno sa jednim Accord
in the temple and breaking bread from
u hramu i razbijanje kruha
house to house they ate their food with
kuću u kuću sa kojom su jeli
gladness and simplicity of heart
radost i jednostavnost srca
praising God and having favor with all
slaviti Boga i imati milost sa svima
the people and the Lord added to the
ljudi i Gospod dodali su
church daily those who were being saved
svakodnevno crkve one koji su bili spašeni
they came together they had everything
došli su zajedno, imali su sve
in common that's a work of the Holy
to je zajedničko djelo Svetog
Spirit right there yes it is how many
Duh tamo da je to koliko
times you get a big group of people
puta kada dobijete veliku grupu ljudi
together it's like you just don't yeah
zajedno je kao da jednostavno ne
you just might not get along with
možda se nećete slagati
everybody just might not but he smooth
svi jednostavno ne mogu, ali je glatko
things over cuz love coke covers over a
stvari preko cuz ljubavi koks prekriva preko
multitude of sins God's love is
mnoštvo greha Božja ljubav je
transformative in our lives yeah they
transformativni u našim životima da oni
sold stuff yeah they met needs yes this
prodali su stvari da su ispunili potrebe da to
is him everyone was filled with awe and
je on bio ispunjen strahopoštovanjem i
many wonders and miraculous signs were
bilo je mnogo čudesa i čudesnih znakova
done by the apostles and this wasn't
učinili su je apostoli i to nije bilo
just to do miraculous signs and wonders
samo radi čudesnih znakova i čuda
it was in order to draw people to the
to je bilo da bi se ljudi privukli
Lord it was to testify to who Jesus was
Gospodine, trebalo je da posvedočim ko je bio Isus
right and and so that's what drew more
desno i tako je to više privuklo
people to them so you have this this
ljudi za njih, tako da imate ovo ovo
inward they devoted themselves to the
unutra su se posvetili
Apostles teaching into the fellowship
Apostoli uče u zajedništvo
breaking and bread this communion and
razbijanje i hleb ovog zajedništva i
prayer and then so that's internal
molitva i onda je to unutrašnje
that's our group and then the Apostles
to je naša grupa i onda apostoli
did these wonderful miracles and that
učinio je ova divna čuda i to
one
jedan
and just inside the group I don't think
i samo unutar grupe ne mislim
I think it like kids we're told and the
Mislim da je reč o deci kojoj je rečeno
rest of Acts how Jane Eyre Peter and
ostatak Dela kako Jane Eyre Peter i
John would go walking and if Peters
John će ići hodati i ako Peters
shadow fell on someone they are healed
sjena je pala na nekoga koga su ozdravili
right so that's an external thing and
tako da je to vanjska stvar i
yes miracles are done inside the church
Da, čuda su učinjena unutar crkve
I've no problem that but it's also
Ja nemam problem, ali je i to
outside the church as well for the
i izvan crkve
purpose of you know pointing people to
Svrha je da znate na koje ljude
Jesus miracles are not done to point the
Isusova čuda nisu učinjena kako bi pokazala
to us miracles and an AA and and wonders
nama čuda i AA i čuda
are done to point people to Jesus yeah
učinjeno je da se ljudi upućuju Isusu da
and so I find that very interesting and
i zato smatram da je to vrlo zanimljivo i
because then they come back in and all
jer se onda vraćaju unutra i sve
the believers were together and had
vjernici su bili zajedno i imali su
everything in common selling their
sve zajedničko prodaje svoje
possessions and good and gave to
imovine i dobro i dao
everyone as he had need Kerry is very
svi kao što mu je bilo potrebno Kerry je vrlo
good at this we were uh we picked up a
dobra u ovome smo uh smo pokupili
young lady to go to school and I sent
mlada dama da ide u školu i ja sam poslao
her she's in grade 8 and I said where
ona je u 8. razredu i ja sam rekao gde
are your mittens and she's just like I
su tvoje rukavice i ona je kao ja
forgot grade eight girls and really
Zaboravio sam devojke osmog razreda i stvarno
they're just too cool to dress for
oni su previše kul za oblačenje
winter and it was winter here in Canada
zima i zima je bila ovdje u Kanadi
I am cold and I said where are your
Hladno mi je i rekao sam gdje su tvoji
mittens and like little cold no scarf
rukavice i kao malo hladno bez marame
jacket open and Here I am asking you
jakna otvoreni i Evo ja vas pitam
about mins cuz we're all like bundled up
O mins cuz smo svi kao u paketu
right to the top hat to this who cares
pravo na šešir za koga je to briga
about being cool now really and so she's
o tome kako je sada stvarno cool i tako je
like I don't have any and so what did
kao da ja nemam i šta je bilo
Carrie do she's like well here I have an
Carrie je da je dobro ovde
extra pair i just gave and I'm like you
dodatni par sam dao i ja sam kao ti
like those minton and she didn't even
poput onih mintona, a ona nije
didn't even bat an eye and I'm like
nisam čak ni šišao oko i ja sam kao
that's what that means that's what that
to je ono što to znači da je ono što taj
passage means where you just like give
prolaz znači gdje vam se sviđa
things because there is a need and um I
stvari zato što postoji potreba i um I
know sometimes I struggle with that one
znam da se ponekad borim sa tim
sometimes sometimes it's hard yeah my
ponekad je ponekad teško
mittens are one thing but I've been
rukavice su jedna stvar, ali ja sam bio
challenged with other things too like
suočeni s drugim stvarima previše
maybe it's money that God's asking you
možda je to novac koji te Bog pita
to give like there's some who really has
dati kao da ima nekih koji zaista imaju
need and you think well they might not
trebate i dobro mislite da ne bi mogli
use it appropriately or whatever we've
koristite ga na odgovarajući način ili šta god mi imamo
talked about this another episode and so
razgovarali o ovoj drugoj epizodi i tako
maybe I just don't want to give but I
možda jednostavno ne želim da dam, ali ja
just challenge you and I am at the same
samo vas izazov i ja sam u istom
time feeling challenged and reminded of
vrijeme osjeća izazov i podsjetio
this
ovo
to be a crazy giver hmm like let's just
da budem ludi davalac hmm kao da jesmo
decide this week that if god brings
odlučite ove nedelje da ako Bog donese
something up that we need to give you're
nešto što vam moramo dati
going to give it and then watch what God
daću ga i onda paziti šta Bog
does because they've been so many times
radi zato što su bili toliko puta
where I think oh man I don't know if I
gde ja mislim o čoveče ne znam da li sam
can give that but I just do it and God
to mogu dati, ali ja to radim i Bog
like totally meets my needs in some
kao da potpuno zadovoljava moje potrebe u nekim
other way amazing ways so maybe you know
na neki drugi način neverovatne načine pa možda znate
about talking about miracles maybe
možda o pričama o čudima
that's how God is going to work a
tako će Bog raditi
miracle in their life mm-hmm that you
čudo u svom životu mm-hmm da si ti
are going to be the answer of prayer for
će biti odgovor na molitve za
them but then he is going to in turn be
ali onda će on opet biti
working in your life because of your
radite u vašem životu zbog vašeg
obedience to give so I want to just
poslušnost da dam tako da želim samo
challenged you actually if you have a
osporili ste vas ako imate
miracle story like maybe you have been
Čudesna priča kao da si možda bila
the recipient of something amazing or
primalac nečeg neverovatnog ili
seeing a wonderful healing or maybe
vidim divno lečenje ili možda
you've been a crazy giver and God has
bio si ludi davalac i Bog ima
met your need I just challenged you to
upoznao sam vašu potrebu
actually record your story so get get on
zapravo snimite vašu priču tako da nastavite
your iPhone record a selfie video and
vaš iPhone snima video snimak i selfie
then i challenge you to post it on
onda vas pozivam da ga objavite
facebook mm-hmm and talk about the
facebook mm-hmm i pričaj o
wonderful works of God maybe you want to
divna djela Boga možda želite
go on to our Facebook page under new
idite na našu Facebook stranicu pod novom
every day and post your video I would
svaki dan i postavljam vaš video
love to hear your stories and just be
volim čuti vaše priče i biti samo
challenged to be a crazy giver this
izazvan da bude ludi davalac
church there was no one who had me
u crkvi nije bilo nikoga ko me je imao
because they sold their stuff gathered
jer su prodali svoje stvari sakupljene
there what they had and then met the
tamo su imali ono što su imali, a onda su se sreli
needs of the people and I not know we're
potrebe ljudi i ne znam da smo
gonna take a break be right back
će se odmah vratiti
you think those two bugs are alive oh no
Misliš da su te dve bubice žive?
they've been done okay there's been an
U redu je, bilo je
incredible con that's occurred in the
neverovatan sukob koji se desio u
culture evolution and millions of years
evolucija kulture i milioni godina
is the greatest myth ever forced on the
je najveći mit ikada prisiljen na
minds of men Big Bang evolution people
umovi ljudi Big Bang evolucije ljudi
just believe it blindly how can you not
Upravo to vjeruju slijepo kako se ne možemo
believe that somebody designed all this
Vjerujem da je netko sve ovo osmislio
we know he exists because of creation
znamo da on postoji zbog stvaranja
anyone who denies that as a fool it's
svako ko negira da je to budala
not just faith we have science it's
ne samo vera koju imamo nauku
really on our side and welcome back to
zaista na našoj strani i dobrodošli u
new every day we're in part four of our
novi svaki dan smo u četvrtom dijelu našeg
four-part series on the adventure begins
Počinje serija od četiri dijela o avanturi
Jesus has given the mission he's built
Isus je dao misiju koju je izgradio
the team he's given the power of the
tim je dao moć
Holy Spirit and now it's actually the
Sveti Duh i sada je to zapravo
walking it out and they're doing it in
izašao sam i oni to rade
something called Church and what's
nešto što se zove Crkva i šta je
interesting is we talked a little bit
Zanimljivo je da smo malo razgovarali
beforehand how they were in perfect
unaprijed kako su bili u savršenom
unity nobody had any need and you know
jedinstvo niko nije imao potrebu i ti znaš
amazing signs and wonders were happening
događaju se čudesni znakovi i čuda
and the question that comes to mind is
i pitanje koje mi pada na pamet je
yeah that was then but what about now
da, to je bilo tada, ali sada
like am I seeing that happen in our
kao što vidim da se to događa u našem
church and so many people said well that
crkva i mnogi ljudi su to dobro rekli
was the Apostolic age like that apply to
bilo je apostolsko doba
now does not apply to now and all I can
sada se ne odnosi na sada i sve što mogu
think about was I don't think Jesus has
Razmisli o tome da mislim da Isus nije
stopped has said don't be generous
prestao je rekao da ne budem velikodušan
anymore because I don't be right and I
više zato što nisam u pravu i ja
don't think it's almost a shame it's
nemoj misliti da je skoro šteta
called the Acts of the Apostles because
nazvali su Dela apostolska zato što
it's really the act of Jesus right and
to je u stvari Isusovo pravo i
talks about the Holy Spirit but it's the
govori o Svetom Duhu, ali to je
act of Jesus right what he has done and
Isus je ispravno postupio i učinio
he's still doing that good work right
još uvek dobro radi
yeah and so yes the apostles were
da i tako su apostoli bili
carrying it out but they were carrying
nošenje, ali su nosili
it out to the next generation to the
to je za sledeću generaciju
next generation and so that's why Paul
sledeće generacije i zato je Paul
sets up like this is the way the church
postavlja se ovako je crkva
is supposed to look and like this is
trebalo bi da izgleda i ovako je
what it's supposed to do and and and so
šta treba da uradi i što i tako
no I don't when I read this passage I
ne, ne čitam ovaj odlomak I
don't think no that was just for that
ne mislim da je to bilo samo za to
now are we supposed to you know give up
sada smo trebali da znate da odustajete
you know our homes or single homes and
znate naše domove ili pojedinačne kuće i
then come together well no that's not
onda se dobro slažete, nije to
were saying but maybe this but if God
govorili, ali možda ovo, ali ako Bog
calls you
poziva vas
to that then the answer is yes like one
onda je odgovor da kao jedan
of the reasons why Carrie and I choose
o razlozima zbog kojih Carrie i ja biramo
to share space together is one it is
dijeliti prostor zajedno je jedan
cheaper but that money then allows us to
jeftinije ali novac nam to dozvoljava
spend it on other things that God is
trošite ga na druge stvari koje je Bog
calling us to because the thing is we
zovemo nas jer je stvar u nama
could say no I want my own space but
mogao bih reći ne želim svoj prostor, ali
then we would be paying you know two and
onda bismo vam platili da znate dva i
three times the amount and then you know
tri puta više od toga i onda znate
you are strapped to do what God has
ti si vezan da radiš ono što Bog ima
called you to do and I had at one point
pozvao sam vas da uradite i ja sam u jednom trenutku
I was looking about buying a house and a
Tražio sam da kupim kuću i
lady said to me well Jen what does God
dama mi je dobro rekla Jen šta Bog čini
calling you to do because know that even
Zove te da radiš zato što to znaš
though the bank will give you this much
iako će vam banka dati toliko toga
money know that you also like to give it
novac Znam da ste također željeli da ga
the church you sponsor people like in
crkve vi sponzor ljudi kao u
mish ever mission missionaries you go on
mish ikada misija misija ste ići na
vacation like what is the lifestyle God
odmor kao što je životni Bog
has called you to and then that is the
vas je pozvao i onda je to
house actually that you need to live in
kuća zapravo u kojoj trebate živjeti
and several times Carrie and I have you
i nekoliko puta Carrie i ja imamo tebe
know if we ever if God ever calls us on
znajte da li nas ikada Bog pozove
from the spot where we're living now the
sa mesta gde sada živimo
fact that no we would love the house
činjenica da ne bismo voleli kuću
that would have one or two rooms to open
koja bi imala jednu ili dvije sobe za otvaranje
up for ministry purposes to share with
za potrebe ministarstva da podele sa njima
other people so that they can you know
drugih ljudi, tako da mogu da znate
save money and do the things God has
uštedite novac i radite ono što Bog ima
called them to and but that's a god
pozvao ih je, ali to je bog
thing yeah it has to be a god glad thing
Da, to mora biti božja radost
and that's why we've always said we will
i zato smo uvek govorili da hoćemo
be in this location until God calls us
biti na ovoj lokaciji dok nas Bog ne pozove
somewhere else because we want to do
negdje drugdje, jer želimo da uradimo
what God wants us to and that's you know
ono što Bog želi i to znate
through the power of the Holy Spirit and
kroz snagu Svetog Duha i
so when this passage says that they
pa kad ovaj pasus kaže da su oni
continue to meet together in the temple
nastavljaju da se sastaju zajedno u hramu
courts they broke bread in their homes
sudovima su razbijali hleb u svojim domovima
ate together with glad and sincere
jeli zajedno sa radošću i iskrenošću
hearts praising God and enjoying the
srca slave Boga i uživaju
favor of all the people and the Lord
naklonost svih ljudi i Gospodina
added to their number daily so obviously
dodao je njihov broj dnevno tako očigledno
people from outside we're seeing how
ljudi izvana vide kako
they were treating others inside and
tretirali su druge unutar i
they wanted to join yeah and so one of
htjeli su da se pridruže i tako i jedan od njih
the big big questions is is this
veliko pitanje je da li je ovo
happening in your church right and if
desilo se u vašoj crkvi i ako
not then why not yeah and so what we
ne onda zašto ne i tako što mi
want to blame someone else well this
Želim da okrivim nekog drugog dobro
team isn't doing their thing or this
tim ne radi svoju stvar ili ovo
team isn't doing their thing and I think
tim ne radi svoju stvar i ja mislim
we have to come right back and point to
moramo se vratiti i pokazati
ourselves say well am i doing my thing
sami kažemo da dobro radim svoju stvar
like am I willing to break bread with
kao što sam voljan da razbijem hleb
other believers am I willing to welcome
druge vjernike sam spreman dočekati
people into my home am i praying like
ljudi u moj dom se i ja tako molim
this
ovo
all part of it am I praising God like am
sve je to dio koji hvalim Boga kao što sam ja
I actually showing up to church on
Ja se zapravo pojavljujem u crkvi
Sunday morning and participating or am i
Nedjeljom ujutro i sudjelovanjem ili ja
there just sort of sitting feed me feed
tamo mi samo hrani hranu
me in the app okay it's time to go by
ja u aplikaciji u redu je vrijeme da prođe
and then we wonder why God is in you
i onda se pitamo zašto je Bog u vama
know using us or doing amazing things
znaju da koriste nas ili radite neverovatne stvari
was because we only come in plonk
bilo je zato što smo došli samo u plonku
ourselves down up and now at the door
i sami na vratima
but we actually haven't interacted with
ali mi zapravo nismo sarađivali
anyone we haven't shared our stories we
bilo koga koga nismo podijelili s nama
haven't listened to other people we
nismo slušali druge ljude
haven't prayed for other people we
nismo se molili za druge ljude
aren't aware of the needs of others
nisu svjesni potreba drugih
because we haven't actually done our
jer nismo zapravo uradili naše
part and then we blame the church for
i onda krivimo crkvu
not encouraging us or not inspiring us
ne ohrabruje nas ili nas ne inspiriše
and I'm thinking this haven't been part
i mislim da ovo nije bilo deo
of it I know like this passage alone
to znam samo kao ovaj pasus
should be inspiring enough for us to say
trebalo bi da nas dovoljno inspiriše da kažemo
wait a second Jesus gave his mission go
sačekajte sekund Isus je dao svoju misiju
into all the world he gave us the team
u celom svetu nam je dao tim
which is the church then he'd the gas in
to je crkva, a onda je on ušao u gas
the car he gave the Holy Spirit that is
automobil koji je dao Svetom Duhu koji je
all you need we don't need to be asking
sve što nam treba je da ne pitamo
i wonder what God wants us to do yeah
Pitam se šta Bog želi da radimo da
wait goods true he's already told us
Čekajte robu istinu koju nam je već rekao
he's already told us and so if you've
Već nam je rekao, pa ako imate
been waiting to know what is God asked
čekali su da znaju šta je Bog tražio
asking you to do we encourage you to
tražimo od vas da vas ohrabrimo
read these first two chapters of Acts
pročitajte ova prva dva poglavlja Dela
and just be inspired again that Jesus is
i samo budite ponovo nadahnuti da je Isus
calling you to share the message of his
Zove te da podeliš njegovu poruku
kingdom with other people that he has
kraljevstvo s drugim ljudima koje ima
provided you a team in the church to
obezbedili ste tim u crkvi
help you with everything that you could
pomoći vam u svemu što ste mogli
ever need and then he's given you the
ikada treba i onda ti je dao
Holy Spirit to lead and guide you yeah
Duh Sveti da vas vodi i vodi
and the whole end up and the church is
i čitav kraj i crkva je
like this this crazy living organism
kao ovaj ludi živi organizam
yeah of people multiple people one body
da ljudi više ljudi jedno tijelo
many parts but one body with Jesus as
mnogo delova, ali jedno telo sa Isusom kao
the head and you are a part of that body
glava i vi ste deo tog tela
has a role to play the Bible says you
ima ulogu u Bibliji
know if the if the foot should say
znam da li bi stopalo trebalo da kaže
because I'm not a hand than I have no
jer nisam ruka nego što nemam
part in the body well that's not true
dobro je to u tijelu, to nije istina
because if the your vehicle munoz that
jer ako je vaše vozilo munoz to
I'm not part if I'm if I'm not a nose or
Nisam deo ako nisam nos ili
if I aminals yeah essentially each part
ako sam aminals da u suštini svaki dio
has a role to play yeah so encourage you
ima ulogu da igraš da ohrabruješ
this week to pray and look at your role
ove nedelje da se pomolimo i pogledamo vašu ulogu
yeah is it being a crazy giver yeah in
Da, to je ludi darivatelj
one instance yeah I'm not saying that
jedan primer da ne kažem to
you have to take on a specified role in
morate uzeti na određeno ulogu u
the church like
kao u crkvi
have a title but you are part of that
imate naslov, ali vi ste deo toga
body and you can meet needs in
telo i možete zadovoljiti potrebe
conversation yes in bringing a meal in
razgovor da donosim obrok
phoning a new person in shaking their
telefoniranja nova osoba u odmahuju
hand yeah I'm warning in inviting your
ruku da upozoravam na poziv
coworker to church that so many ways so
coworker u crkvi da je tako mnogo načina
many ways so we encourage you to take
mnoge načine pa pozivamo Vas da uzmete
this mission that Jesus has given us
ovu misiju koju nam je dao Isus
seriously to take your role in the
ozbiljno da preuzmete svoju ulogu u
church seriously and to submit that to
ozbiljno i da to podnesete
the Holy Spirit saying Lord these are
Sveti Duh koji govori Gospodu su oni
the things I'm struggling with because
stvari sa kojima se borim
often is the things that we struggled
često su stvari koje smo se borili
with that hold us back but when we turn
s tim što nas zadržavaju, ali kad se okrenemo
them over to the Holy Spirit said this
oni su pred Svetim Duhom rekli ovo
is what I'm struggling with I don't even
to je ono s čim se borim, čak ni ne
like the church that I'm at or I don't
kao crkva u kojoj sam ili ne
even like the passer I don't like the
čak i kao prolaznik koji mi se ne sviđa
person i'm sitting beside and yet this
osoba koju sedim pored ovoga
is where i am could you help me and you
gde sam ja mogao da mi pomognete i vama
know what there are times where I've
znam šta ima vremena gde sam
prayed that prayer and God has totally
molio se da je molitva i Bog potpuno
shown up it's okay to pray those prayers
Pokazalo se da je u redu moliti te molitve
because that is where I think the many
jer tu mislim da mnogi
wonders and miraculous signs happens
čuda i čudesni znaci
sometimes where he just comes and he
ponekad gde samo dolazi i on
gives us starts giving us a love and
daje nam početak i daje nam ljubav
understanding he opens her eyes but are
razumevanje on otvara oči, ali jesu
we willing to actually be honest with
mi smo spremni da budemo iskreni
the things that were struggling with
stvari koje su se mučile
with the mission because i'm going back
sa misijom zato što se vraćam
to set sail boat baggins and he
da isplovi brodom Baggins, a on
struggled with his role on the team they
borili su se sa svojom ulogom u timu
said well he's a thief right like they
dobro je rekao da je lopov kao oni
had him to be a thief he's like I'm not
ga je da bude lopov on je kao da nisam
a thief I don't do anything wrong and
lopov ne radim ništa loše
then he looked at his life is like but
onda je pogledao svoj život, ali je
I'm so comfortable and look at my teeth
Tako mi je udobno i gledam zube
my cheese and look at all these things
moj sir i pogledaj sve te stvari
in my home I don't want to leave my home
u mojoj kući ne želim napustiti svoj dom
and comfortable but if he had not gone
i udobno, ali da nije otišao
and stepped out he would have missed out
i izašao je da bi propustio
on the greatest adventure of his life
na najveću avanturu u svom životu
yes so we encourage you today to maybe
Da, ohrabrujemo vas danas
let go of some of what you find security
oslobodite se onoga što nađete u sigurnosti
and and embrace the mission that God is
i prihvatiti misiju koju Bog ima
called you know that the Holy Spirit is
pozvani ste da znate da je Sveti Duh
going to guide you and that a church
će vas voditi i crkvu
that church and a local church will
ta crkva i lokalna crkva će
equip you for all you need so be
opremite se za sve što vam je potrebno
encouraged the Lord is with you have a
ohrabren Gospod je sa vama ima
great week have a great week serving the
veliki tjedan imaju veliki tjedan u službi
Lord
Gospode
amen amen
amen amen
you
vas